// variables to play light game
//one question, four possible answer and 1 correct answer 
let lightQuestions = [{
    //Easy questions
    question: "Which Star wars faction fights against the Empire?",
    correctAnswer: "REBEL ALLIANCE",
    answerOne: "REBEL LEAGUE",
    answerTwo: "REBEL CONFEDERATION",
    answerThree: "REBEL ALLIANCE",
    answerFour: "REBEL COALITION",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of the mystical power used by Jedi Knights in Star Wars?",
    correctAnswer: "THE FORCE",
    answerOne: "THE FORCE",
    answerTwo: "THE POWER",
    answerThree: "THE EFFORT",
    answerFour: "THE ENERGY",
  },
  {
    question: "What main colors are two famous droids C-3P0 and R2-D2?",
    correctAnswer: "GOLDEN AND BLUE ",
    answerOne: "GOLDEN AND RED",
    answerTwo: "SILVER AND BLACK",
    answerThree: "GOLDEN AND BLUE ",
    answerFour: "SILVER AND RED",
  },
  {
    question: "What color is the first lightsaber Luke uses?",
    correctAnswer: "BLUE",
    answerOne: "RED",
    answerTwo: "GREEN",
    answerThree: "WHITE",
    answerFour: "BLUE",
  },
  {
    question: "Who says this: Try not. Do or do not. There is no try.?",
    correctAnswer: "YODA",
    answerOne: "OBI WAN KENOBI",
    answerTwo: "LUKE SKYWALKER",
    answerThree: "YODA",
    answerFour: "HAN SOLO",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of these characters appear to be twins?",
    correctAnswer: "LEIA AND LUKE",
    answerOne: "HAN AND LUKE",
    answerTwo: "HAN AND LEIA",
    answerThree: "LEIA AND LUKE",
    answerFour: "LUKE AND DARTH VADER",
  },
  {
    question: "On which planet Luke Skywalker was raised?",
    correctAnswer: "TATOOINE",
    answerOne: "TATOOINE",
    answerTwo: "ANDERAN",
    answerThree: "DAGOBAH",
    answerFour: "DANTOOINE",
  },
  {//Medium difficulty
    question: "What species does Chewbacca belong to?",
    correctAnswer: "WOOKIEE",
    answerOne: "EWOK",
    answerTwo: "HUTT",
    answerThree: "WOOKIEE",
    answerFour: "CHEWEE",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of the ice planet where the rebel base is located?",
    correctAnswer: "HOTH",
    answerOne: "BESPIN",
    answerTwo: "ENDOR",
    answerThree: "HOTH",
    answerFour: "DANTOOINE",
  },
  {
    question: "What is Han Solo's reply to leia's “I love you” right before he is frozen into carbonite on Cloud city? ",
    correctAnswer: "I KNOW",
    answerOne: "FIND ME",
    answerTwo: "ME TOO",
    answerThree: "I LOVE YOU TOO",
    answerFour: "I KNOW",
  },
  {
    question: "Which small creatures live on the planet Endor?",
    correctAnswer: "EWOKS",
    answerOne: "WOOKIES",
    answerTwo: "JAWAS",
    answerThree: "WAMPA",
    answerFour: "EWOKS",
  },
  //Difficult questions
  {
    question: "Who finds Luke Skywalker in the snow and saves him from freezing to dead?",
    correctAnswer: "HAN SOLO",
    answerOne: "LEIA",
    answerTwo: "OBI WAN KENOBI",
    answerThree: "HAN SOLO",
    answerFour: "CHEWBACCA",
  },
  {
    question: "Cloud City, the mining run by Lando Calrissan, specialized in what resource?",
    correctAnswer: " TIBANNA",
    answerOne: " TIBANNA",
    answerTwo: "CARBON",
    answerThree: "KYBER STONES",
    answerFour: "BESKAR",
  },
  {
    question: "What was Luke's call sign during the battle of Yavin?",
    correctAnswer: "RED FIVE",
    answerOne: "RED FIVE",
    answerTwo: "RED LEADER",
    answerThree: "THE EFFORT",
    answerFour: "GOLD FOUR",
  },
  {
    question: "Princess Leia is captured aboard which spaceship at the beginning of “A New Hope”?",
    correctAnswer: "TANTIV IV",
    answerOne: "SLAVE I",
    answerTwo: "STAR DESTROYER",
    answerThree: "TANTIV IV",
    answerFour: "MILLENNIUM FACOLN",
  },
  {
    question: "Cloud City, the mining run by Lando Calrissan, specialized in what resource?",
    correctAnswer: "TIBANNA",
    answerOne: "TIBANNA",
    answerTwo: "CARBON",
    answerThree: "KYBER STONES",
    answerFour: "BESKAR",
  },
];

// variables to play dark game
//one question, four possible answer and 1 correct answer 
let darkQuestions = [{
  //Easy questions
  question: "What planet does the Empire choose to destroy first, in order to demonstrate the destructive capability of the Death Star?",
  correctAnswer: "ALDERAAN",
  answerOne: "ALDERAAN",
  answerTwo: "YAVIN",
  answerThree: "BESPIN",
  answerFour: "DANTOOINE",
},
{
  question: "What is the name of the bounty hunter that delivered a frozen Han Solo to Jabba The HUTT?",
  correctAnswer: " BOBA FETT",
  answerOne: " BOBA FETT",
  answerTwo: "BOSSK",
  answerThree: "IG-88",
  answerFour: "GREEDO",
},{
  question: "Where does Darth Vader tell Luke that he is his father? ",
  correctAnswer: "CLOUD CITY",
  answerOne: "DEATH STAR",
  answerTwo: "ENDOR",
  answerThree: "CLOUD CITY",
  answerFour: "DEATH STAR II",
},{
  question: "What is the name of the empire's soldiers line up during the battle of Hoth?",
  correctAnswer: "SNOWTROOPERS",
  answerOne: "SNOWTROOPERS",
  answerTwo: "SPACETROOPERS",
  answerThree: "SNOW LEGIONNAIRS",
  answerFour: "STORMTOOPERS",
},{
  question: "What is the main color of Darth Vader's lightsaber? ",
  correctAnswer: "RED",
  answerOne: "PURPLE",
  answerTwo: "BLUE",
  answerThree: "RED",
  answerFour: "WHITE",
},{
  question: "What superweapon does the Galactic Empire control?",
  correctAnswer: "DEATH STAR",
  answerOne: "DEATH STAR",
  answerTwo: "STAR DESTROYER",
  answerThree: "MOON DESTROYER",
  answerFour: "BLACK STAR",
},{
  question: "The second Death Star is constructed near which forest moon?",
  correctAnswer: "ENDOR",
  answerOne: "YAVIN IV",
  answerTwo: "DAGOBAH",
  answerThree: "BESPIN",
  answerFour: "ENDOR",
},
{//medium questions
  question: "Which of these characters gets killed by Darth Vader in “ A New Hope”?",
  correctAnswer: "OBI WAN KENOBI",
  answerOne: "YODA",
  answerTwo: "CHEWBACCA",
  answerThree: "OBI WAN KENOBI",
  answerFour: "HAN SOLO",
},
{
  question: "What is the name of The Emperor of the Galactic Empire in Star Wars?",
  correctAnswer: "PALPATINE",
  answerOne: "ANAKIN",
  answerTwo: "DARTH VADER ",
  answerThree: "PALPATINE",
  answerFour: "PLAGUEIS",
},{
  question: "What was the name of Vader's Super Star Destroyer?",
  correctAnswer: "EXECUTOR",
  answerOne: "DEVASTATOR",
  answerTwo: "EXECUTOR",
  answerThree: "CONQUEROR",
  answerFour: "IMPERATOR",
},{
  question: "What is the name of the giant four-legged walkers used by the Empire during the battle of Hoth?",
  correctAnswer: " AT-AT",
  answerOne: "AT_ST",
  answerTwo: "FIGHTERS",
  answerThree: " AT-AT",
  answerFour: "INTERCEPTOR",
},
//difficult questions
{
  question: "What was the name of Baba Fett's ship?",
  correctAnswer: "SLAVE I ",
  answerOne: "SLAVE I ",
  answerTwo: "NEBULON I",
  answerThree: "SLAVE II",
  answerFour: "BOUNTY I",
},{
  question: "What is the name of the giant beast species that lives under Jabba's throne room?",
  correctAnswer: "RANCOR",
  answerOne: "WAMPA",
  answerTwo: "TAUNTAUN",
  answerThree: "RANCOR",
  answerFour: "SARLAC",
},{
  question: "Which character is the commander of the Death Star?",
  correctAnswer: "MOFF TARKIN",
  answerOne: "ADMIRAL OZZEL",
  answerTwo: "MOFF TARKIN",
  answerThree: "GENERAL VEERS",
  answerFour: "LORD NEEDA",
},{
  question: "What creature lived in the trash compactor of the Death Star?",
  correctAnswer: "DIANOGA",
  answerOne: "SARLAC",
  answerTwo: "RANCOR",
  answerThree: "TUSKEN",
  answerFour: "DIANOGA",
}
];